Abderrahman Lahiaouni



SUMMARY

"Research and development engineer, graduated from an engineering school in a well known university, experience extends from IT consulting to research, relevant technical skills as well as communication skills working in positions involving marketing and public relations as well as traveling. Fast learner, excited to see new things, with a strong sense of commitment, fellowship and cheerfulness" 10-06-2019

WORK EXPERIENCE

CURRENT, SINCE DEC 2018 (FT)

Institut National de Recherche en Informatique et en Automatique lille

Research and development engineer

Currently working on a project that aims to push the boundaries of formal verification of large complex software systems described with formal specification languages by leveraging Grid5000 research infrastructure capabilities, by making big SAT problems that are slow to solve locally, deployable remotely in the Grid5000, and provide convenient result retrieval and reporting, a portal will handle requests by making reservations, configuring and deploying clusters automatically using Ansible, Kubernetes and Docker Machine, running jobs, storing results in a Ceph cluster making them available to the client

MAI 2018 - NOV 2018 (FT)

Institut National de Recherche en Informatique et en Automatique lille

Intern for Final Project assignment

As part of the spirals team, my team is particularly interested in introducing more automation in the adaptation mechanisms of software systems. I worked on a project about cloud storage, more specifically on load balancing and data replication. The focus was on practical outcomes concerning data popularity, network traffic and available capacity, and how they could be the factors to route requests, to decide when, what data, and where to place replicas to ensure data availability and optimize resource usage.

JUL 2017 - SEP 2017 (FT)

Algo Consulting group Summer internship

First experience in professional environment. The transition required an initial learning curve acquiring .NET, Xamarin.Forms, and understanding agile project management, i was part of one of the production teams which wasn't an option for summer interns, integrated an ongoing project as a part of the dev-ops team thanks to willingness to learn, quick adaptation and mostly the manager and seniors great support. We used Microsoft Azure to host production databases and deploy services, adopting SCRUM framework. I was mainly in charge of building UI for business logic, and for fixing problems we get from testing engineers reports and clients feedback between sprints.

single, 25yo

81 bis Boulevard Montebello 59000 Lille

130 Av Abi Katada Assif c Marrakech Maroc

+33 6 24 94 37 58 C

lahiaouni.abd@gmail.com ewline

https://www.linkedin.com/in/lahiaouniabderrahman/

EDUCATION

Engineer degree 2013 - 2018

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

National School of Applied Sciences

baccalaureate 2012

Department of Math

Rahaly El Farouq High school

TRAINING

Test Driven Development – INRIA Lille

Introduction and live programming using python, pytest,

Data mining - ENSA Marrakech

Introduction and workshop using weka

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible TOOLS

> ssh, openSSL, bash maven, git, gitlab ci OpenAPI Swagger

PROGRAMMING JavaSE, Android SDK, SQL

> JavaEE, .Net Standard Library Golang, Javascript, Python, Php, C

C++

COMMUNICATION SKILLS

Intervention - More Intelligent Web SCHOOL EVENTS

> Software engineer day – 2017 Workshop – .Net boot-camp Workshop – Microservices design Workshop - The Blockchain

Arabic native language LANGUAGES

> French English

PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

Goal Oriented

I believe in action over long-winded discussions. I listen to everyone's viewpoints and use my judgment to immediately act based on consensus to achieve goals quickly and efficiently.

Passionate

I have been interested in computer sciences from an early age. Education and research have cemented this interest into a passion. I greatly enjoy carrying out fundamental and technical aspects in IT with practical and useful applications.